片名:森林王子
Many strange legends are told of these jungles of India,
印度丛林故事 总是充满神秘的色彩
but none so strange as the story of a small boy named Mowgli.
其中又以毛克利的故事最是
It all began when the silence of the jungle was broken
记得那一天安静的森林
by an unfamiliar sound.
突然传来一种陌生的声音
It was a sound like one never heard before
这个声音 可以说是我从来没听过的
in this part of the jungle.
It was a man cub!
是……是人类的一个小家伙！
Had I known how deeply I was to be involved,
哦，我的直觉告诉我少管闲事
I would've obeyed my first impulse and walked away.
但是 我还是忍不住管了闲事
This man cub would have to have nourishment, and soon.
这孩子这么小
It was many days' travel to the nearest man-village,
离人类的村落又那么远
and without a mother's care, he would soon perish.
没有妈妈的照顾 他绝对活不了多久
Then it occurred to me.
呃，对了
A family of wolves I knew had been blessed with a litter of cubs.
前不久野狼家 才生了一窝小宝宝
I knew there'd be no problem with the mother, thanks to the maternal instinct,
大自然创造的母性 就是这么纯朴实在
but I wasn't so sure about Rama, the father.
不过，我还是有点担心 爸爸阿利的表现
Ten times, the rains had come and gone,
十几个寒暑一转眼就过去了
and I often stopped by
我经常去看毛克利
to see how Mowgli, the man cub, was getting along.
He was a favourite with all the young wolf cubs of the pack.
那个小家伙长得还真好
No man cub was ever happier.
小野狼都很喜欢他
And yet, I knew that someday
不过，我知道只要时候到了
he would have to go back to his own kind.
他就得回到他的村落
Then one night, the wolf pack elders met at Council Rock
一个晚上野狼族聚在一起 开了岩石大会
because Shere Khan, the tiger,
原来是老虎谢利 回到了森林
had returned to their part of the jungle.
This meeting was to change the man cub's entire future.
这个会议改变了 小家伙的后半生
Shere Khan will surely kill the boy and all who try to protect him.
谢利会杀了小家伙 连我们也很危险
Now, are we all in agreement as to what must be done?
现在我们必须同意这个选择
Now it is my unpleasant duty to tell the boy's father.
虽然是很难启口 我还是得告诉阿利
Rama. Come over here, please.
阿利，麻烦你过来一下
Yes, Akela?
什么事啊？阿格拉
The council has reached its decision.
大会做出了一致的决定
The man cub can no longer stay with the pack.
那个小家伙不能 住在我们这里
He must leave at once.
他必须立刻离开这里
"Leave"?
为什么？
I'm sorry, Rama. There is no other way.
对不起，阿利 我们也没有办法
But the man cub is...
可是……可是这个小家伙
Well, he's like my own son.
就像我亲生的儿子
Surely he's entitled to the protection of the pack.
不管怎么说 我们应该一起保护他呀
But, Rama, even the strength of the pack is no match for the tiger.
阿利，全野狼族加起来 也打不过谢利啊
But the boy cannot survive alone in the jungle.
小家伙一个人在丛林里 怎么过呢
Akela, perhaps I can be of help.
阿格拉，交给我吧
You, Bagheera? How?
你，巴希拉？能吗？
I know of a man-village where he'll be safe.
他最好回到人类的村落
Mowgli and I have taken many walks into the jungle together.
毛克利常常跟我一起 在森林里散步
I'm sure he'll go with me.
他会跟我走的
So be it. Now there's no time to lose.
那也好，就别再浪费时间了
Good luck.
快点上路
Bagheera, I'm getting a little sleepy.
巴希拉，我好困啊
Shouldn't we start back home?
我们回家吧
Mowgli, this time we're not going back.
毛克利 从今天起我们不回家了
- I'm taking you to a man-village. - But why?
我要送你去人类的村落 为什么？
Because Shere Khan has returned to this part of the jungle
因为谢利 他又回到森林来称霸
and he has sworn to kill you.
而且他一定会吃了你
Kill me? But why would he want to do that?
吃了我？ 为什么要吃我啊？
He hates man.
他恨人类
Shere Khan is not going to allow you to grow up to become a man,
谢利绝不会让你 在这个地方长大成人的
just another hunter with a gun.
他说人只会举枪杀老虎
We'll just explain to him that I'd never do a thing like that.
哦，那我可以解释给他听 我不是那种人啊
Nonsense. No one explains anything to Shere Khan.
开玩笑 跟谢利是有理说不清的
Well, maybe so, but I'm not afraid.
那就算了，反正我也不怕他
- And besides, I... - Now, that's enough.
呃，再说…… 好了，别说了
We'll spend the night here.
今天咱们在这过夜
Things will look better in the morning.
明天天一亮就没事了
Man Cub?
小家伙？
Man Cub!
小家伙！
Now, come on. Up this tree. It's safer up there.
爬上去，到树上去 上面安全
I don't wanna go back to the man-village.
呃，可是我不想去人类的村落
Go on. Up you go.
来吧！上去
- That limb way up there? - That's right.
要爬那么高啊？ 是啊
Is that all the better you can climb?
爬树哪是这样爬的？
It's too big around.
树干太大了嘛
And besides, I don't have any claws.
再说，我又没有你的爪子
Now get some sleep.
好了，早点睡吧
We've got a long journey ahead of us tomorrow.
我们明天一早要赶路呢
I wanna stay in the jungle.
呃，我要留在森林里
嗯，哈……多留一天也不行
You wouldn't last one day.
I'm not afraid.
我才不怕 我会自己照顾自己的
I can look out for myself.
Say, now.
瞧瞧
What have we here?
谁在这儿呀？
It's a man cub.
一个小家伙
A delicious man cub.
香甜可口的小家伙
Go away and leave me alone.
哦，走开，不要吵我
That's just what I should do, but I'm not.
哦……我也不想吵你 可是你一个人谁放心得下
Now, please go to sleep, Man Cub.
晚了，睡吧，小家伙
Yes, Man Cub.
是啊，小家伙，睡吧
♪ Please go to sleep ♪
小家伙，睡吧
♪ Sleep, little man cub ♪
你已经累了
♪ Rest in peace ♪
要乖乖睡
Sleep.
睡吧
Bagheera...
巴……希拉
Now, look, there's no use arguing any more.
哦，够了，小家伙 没什么好讨论的
Now, no more talk till morning.
有事明儿再说吧
He won't be here in the morning.
明天一早他就不见了
Yes, he will. I...
嗯？哦，不可以的
Kaa! Hold it, Kaa!
卡奥！你干什么？卡奥！
My sinus.
我的线条
You have just made a serious mistake, my friend,
你刚才犯了一个大错了 我的朋友
a very stupid...
一个既愚蠢又危险的……
Now, Kaa, I was...
我……卡奥，我只是……
...mistake.
……错误
Look me in the eye when I'm speaking to you.
看着我的眼睛跟我说话
No, please, Kaa...
卡奥，别……
Both eyes, if you please.
两只眼睛一牵
You have just sealed your doom.
你现在准备面对你的毁灭吧
Look, Bagheera.
你看，巴希拉
Look. Bagheera. Wake up, Bagheera.
看嘛，巴希拉 醒醒啊，巴希拉
Wha...
嗯……啊……
Just you wait till I get you in my coils.
给我等着吧 我会好好修理你的
Bagheera, he's got a knot in his tail!
我把他的尾巴打结了
"He's got a knot in his tail."
打结了
This is going to slow down my slithering.
叫我怎么爬啊
So, you can look out for yourself, can you?
这叫自己照顾自己了？
So, you want to stay in the jungle, do you?
像你这样怎么留在森林里
Yes, I wanna stay in the jungle.
不管，我就不要离开森林
Now, now, for the last time, go to sleep.
好了，好，好了 明天再说，快睡吧
Man cub.
小家伙
♪ Hup, two, three, four ♪
一，二，三，四
♪ Keep it up ♪  ♪ Two, three, four ♪
♪ Hup, two, three, four ♪
继续，一，二，三，四
♪ Keep it up two, three, four ♪
♪ Hup, two, three, four ♪
一，二，三，四
A parade!
一，二，三，四 游行耶！
No.
哦，拜托
The dawn patrol again.
清晨出操
Company, sound off!
预备……唱！
♪ The aim of our patrol ♪
我们全部向前走
♪ Is a question rather droll ♪
迈着大步向前走
♪ For to march and drill over field and hill ♪
跨田野，过上岗
♪ Is a military goal ♪
这是奔走学英雄
♪ Hup, two, three, four ♪
一，二，三，四
♪ Dress it up, two, three, four ♪
继续，一，二，三，四
♪ By the ranks or single file ♪
我们踏步向前走
♪ Over every jungle mile ♪
走进大片丛林中
♪ We stamp and crush through the underbrush ♪
我们践踏踩压 穿过树丛
♪ In the military style ♪
军队就是以上
这是奔走学英雄
Hello. What are you doing?
你好，你在干嘛？
Drilling.
出操
- Can I do it, too? - Sure. Just do what I do.
我能参加吗？ 可以呀，你要跟着我做
But don't talk in ranks. It's against regulations.
可是不能说话哦 出操不能说话
To the rear, march!
向后转……走！
The other way. Turn around.
你错了，向后转
♪ Hup, two, three, four ♪
一，二，三，四
♪ Keep it up, two, three, four ♪
再几个，二，三，四
To the rear...
向后转……
……走！
Company, halt!
立定！
That means "stop."
你要走了啦
Company, left face!
注意，向左转！
March, march, march.
走，走，走
My feet are killing me.
我的脚酸死了
I'm puttin' in for a transfer to another herd.
只要不行军 叫我干嘛都行
Silence in the ranks!
全体立正！
Dress up that line.
屁股翘高
Pull it in, Winifred.
一点精神都没有
Inspection...
全部立正！
Arms!
抬高！
Stick your nose out.
把鼻子抬高
- Like this? - That's right.
像这样？ 对了
A dusty muzzle.
里面脏得跟烟囱一样
Soldier, remember, in battle, that trunk can save your life.
注意，鼻子就是武器 只有它能救你的命
Take good care of it, my man.
给我清干净，听到了吗？
- Yes, sir. - Very good. Carry on.
是，长官 这还差不多
Let's have a little more spit and polish on those bayonets.
一点规矩都不懂 不准吃东西
Yes, sir.
是，长官
Esprit de corps.
我的勋章
That's the way I earned my commission
印度第五世王朝的荣誉勋章
in the Maharajah's Fifth Pachyderm Brigade.
就是这么得来的
Back in '88, it was... Or... Or was it?
记得在60年代 或许更早一点
Here it comes. The Victoria Cross bit again.
又来了 他又老提当年勇了
It was then I received the Victoria Cross,
这是当年 我靠着雪亮的武器
for bravery above and beyond the call of duty.
巡逻王宫多年的成果
Those were the days.
那个时候
Discipline! Discipline was the thing.
军规人人遵守 代表了象的英勇
Builds character and that sort of thing, you know.
没有规矩就不是英雄
所以……嗯
Where was I?
我刚说哪儿了？
Yes. Inspection.
哦，对了，整束仪容
Well, very good.
好极了
Wipe off that silly grin, soldier. This is the army.
不准偷笑，这是军队
Eyes front.
向前看
Lieutenant, that haircut is not regulation.
上尉，你头发不及格
Rather on the gaudy side, don't you think?
仪容要整齐
There. That's better.
呃，这样好看多了
And as for you...
至于你嘛……
There you are.
哦，你在这儿
Let's keep those heels together, shall we, son?
把两脚并拢，好不好 儿子？呃
Okay, Pop.
好，爸爸
- Sir. - Yes, now that's better.
长官 对，这才对嘛
Well, a new recruit, eh?
哦，一位新兵呀？
- I say, what happened to your trunk? - Hey!
奇怪，你的鼻子到哪去了？ 嘿！
Stop that!
你干嘛！
A man cub! This is treason! Sabotage!
人类！哦 这个叛徒想破坏！
I'll have no man cub in my jungle!
人类不能进入我的森林！
- It's not your jungle! - Hold it! Hold it!
森林又不是你的！ 慢着！慢着！
I can explain, Hathi.
让我解释，哈蒂
Colonel Hathi, if you please, sir.
哈蒂上校，注意称呼
Yes, yes. Colonel Hathi.
哦，是……哈蒂上校
The man cub is with me. I'm taking him back to the man-village.
这个小家伙是……是要 跟我回人类的村落
- To stay? - You have the word of Bagheera.
不再回来？ 不回来了，我保证
Good.
很好
And remember, an elephant never forgets.
记住啊，大象记性最好了
I don't know what the army's coming to these days.
现在军队不同了
These young whippersnappers. Who do they think they are?
没有军纪 连礼貌是什么也全忘了
Let's get on with it!
好了，打起精神来！
Right face!
向右转！
Forward march!
齐步……走！
Dear, haven't you forgotten something?
亲爱的 你有没有忘记什么事啊？
Nonsense, Winifred, old girl.
胡说，温妮
An elephant never forgets.
大象的记性最好了
Well, you just forgot our son.
那……你说我们的儿子 上哪儿去了？
Our... Son? Son!
儿子……儿子？我儿子！
Yes, yes, yes. Quite right.
儿子
To the rear, march!
向后转……走！
When I grow up, I'm gonna be a colonel just like my...
等我长大 我也要跟我爸爸一样
If I've told you once, I've told you a thousand times...
儿子啊 我不知道跟你说过多少次了
Pop! Look out!
爸爸！小心！
Gee, Pop, you forgot to say "halt."
好险，你忘记说停呢
He said an elephant never forgets.
他还说大象记性好呢
It's not funny.
有那么好笑吗？
Let's get out of here quick before anything else happens.
我看不太妙 咱们还是快走吧
Bagheera! Where are we goin'?
巴希拉！去哪里啊？
You're going back to the man-village right now.
我现在就送你回人类的村落
I'm not going.
我不要去
- Yes, you are. - I'm staying right here.
不要也得要 我已经决定不走了
You're going, if I have to drag you every step of the way.
就算是用拖的 我今天也要把你拖去
Let go, you...
不走也不行
You let go of me!
你好讨厌啊！
That does it.
我受够了
I've had it, Man Cub.
我再也不会管你了
From now on, you're on your own...
从现在起 你自己照顾自己
Alone!
再见！
Don't worry about me.
有什么了不起的
Foolish man cub.
哎，脾气真倔
♪ Doo-bee, doo-bee ♪  ♪ Doo-bee-dee-doo ♪
嘟吡，嘟吡，嘟吡嘀嘟
♪ Well, it's a-doo-bah-dee-doo ♪
哦真真嘟吡嘀嘟
♪ Yes, it's a-doo-bah-dee-doo ♪
这世界嘟吡嘀嘟
♪ I mean, a-doo-bee, doo-bee ♪  ♪ Doo-bee, doo-bee ♪
充满了嘟吡嘟吡，嘟吡嘟吡
♪ Doo-bee-dee-doo ♪
嘟吡嘀嘟
♪ And with... ♪
嘿
Well, now.
啊，瞧
What have we here?
这是谁呀？
Hey!
啊！嘿！
What a funny little bit of a...
一个好可爱好可爱的小……
Go away!
哦！ 走开！
Oh, boy, I've seen everything in these woods.
哦，好玩 我在这儿可什么都见识过
What have I run on?
还没见过这么可爱的小家伙呢
- What a pretty thing this is. - Leave me alone.
你烦不烦啊
Well, now, that's pretty big talk, Little Britches.
天啊，人不大 口气倒不小啊，小家伙
I'm big enough.
我不小了耶
Pitiful.
Hey, kid, you need help
可笑啊
呃，小家伙，你需要帮忙
and ol' Baloo's gonna learn you to fight like a bear.
让老巴鲁来教你 打架要有熊的架势
Come on. I'm gonna show ya.
来，跟着我学
Yeah!
对了！
All right, now, kid, loosen up.
小家伙，放松自己
Get real loose, then start to weave. Weave a little. Now, move.
左闪右躲，左闪右躲
That's it.
对，现在用力怒吼一声
Now give me a big bear growl. Scare me.
来吓我
Oh, boy.
哦，天啊
I'm talkin' about like a big bear.
我是说要像一只 真正的大熊一样
He's in trouble. I shouldn't have left him alone.
他遇到麻烦了
我……我不应该丢下他
- A big one, right from your toes. - How's that?
大声，用尽全力 怎么样？
You're gettin' it, kid.
真有你的，小家伙
Oh, no! It's Baloo!
哦……惨了！是巴鲁！
That shiftless, stupid jungle bum.
怎么会碰上这个老混球
Weave about now. Look for an opening.
要不停的动 对方才抓不到你
Keep movin'. Keep...
抓住机会就进攻了
You're gettin' it, kid. Come on! That's it!
呃……很好，你进步了 来啊，小家伙
He's a dandy!
对了！就是这样
Fine teacher you are, OI' Iron Paws.
啊，哈……真是好老师啊 铁爪大师
Thanks, Bagheera.
哦，谢了，巴希拉
Tell me, tell me, after you knock your pupil senseless,
嘿，慢点慢点，你出拳那么重 要是打伤了他
how do you expect him to remember the lesson?
你负得起责任吗？
Well, I... I...
哦，呃……
Well, I didn't mean to lay it on him so hard.
我……我没想到耶 你痛不痛啊？
I'm not hurt. I'm all right.
我没事，我很好
I'm a lot tougher than some people think.
我比你们想象的要壮多了
You better believe it.
你是不怎么样了
Now, let's go once more.
来，再来一次
I want you to keep circlin', or I'm gonna knock your roof in again.
我要你不停的动 不然人家就打倒你了
You'd better keep movin'...
要不停的动啊哦
Hey! Right on the button.
哦，呃，正中目标
No. No, no. No, no. Now you're ticklin'.
不要……不要挠我痒了
No. No, now, we don't do that here in the... No!
哦不要，不要 这森林里面不流行这一套的
No, you're ticklin'. I can't stand that ticklin'.
不要，不要，痒死我了 我投降了
Help! Bagheera!
救命！巴希拉！
Oh, boy. That's all he needs, more confidence.
哦，这是你自找的 你自个儿应付
- Give up, Baloo? - I give up, I told ya!
投不投降？ 投降，投降！
I give...
人家投降了嘛
Hey!
嘿！
You know somethin'? You're all right, kid.
小家伙，你挺不错的
What do they call you?
你叫什么名字啊？
Mowgli, and he's going back to the man-village right now.
毛克利 他现在该要回人类的村落了
Man-village? They'll ruin 'im! They'll make a man out of him.
人类村落？那不完了！ 那会毁了他的
Baloo, I wanna stay here with you.
老巴鲁，我想跟你在一起
Certainly, you do.
那当然好啰
And just how do you think he will survive?
是吗？ 那他的问题可就大了
"How do you think..."
你在开什么玩笑啊？ 他一点问题也没有
What do you mean, how do you think he...
He's with me, ain't he? And I'll learn him all I know.
他会跟着我 我会教他所有的事
That shouldn't take too long.
是啊？你会的事也不多
Look, now, it's like this, Little Britches.
放心，只要有我在，小家伙
All you gotta do is...
你只要记住一件事情
♪ Look for the bare necessities ♪
找寻那生活必需品
♪ The simple bare necessities ♪
那单纯生活必需品
♪ Forget about your worries and your strife ♪
忘掉你所有烦恼和忧虑
♪ I mean, the bare necessities ♪
最单纯生活必需品
♪ Are Mother Nature's recipes ♪
充满大自然环境里
♪ That bring the bare necessities of life ♪
不要怕，大自然会供应你
♪ Wherever I wander ♪
不论我是伤心
♪ Wherever I roam ♪
还是我高兴
♪ I couldn't be fonder ♪
只要肚子一饿
♪ Of my big home ♪
就有的吃
♪ The bees are buzzin' in the tree ♪
树枝头蜜蜂嗡嗡 为我做好吃的蜂蜜
♪ To make some honey just for me ♪
♪ When you look under the rocks and plants ♪
只要你翻开大石头就会发现 好吃的蚂蚁
♪ And take a glance at the fancy ants ♪
♪ Then maybe try a few ♪
你要不要试一试？
You eat ants?
吃蚂蚁？
You better believe it.
哈哈！试试看就知道了
And you're gonna love the way they tickle.
你会爱死那种感觉的
Mowgli, look out!
毛克利，当心啊！
♪ The bare necessities of life will come to you ♪
那生活必需品会自动找上你
But when?
真的吗？
♪ They'll come to you ♪
会找上你
♪ Look for the bare necessities ♪
找寻那生活必需品
♪ The simple bare necessities ♪
最单纯生活必需品
♪ Forget about your worries and your strife ♪
忘掉你所有烦恼和忧虑
♪ I mean, the bare necessities ♪
最单纯生活必需品
♪ That's why a bear can rest at ease ♪
像我一样轻松惬意
♪ With just the bare necessities of life ♪
知足常乐你会满心欢喜
♪ Now, when you pick a pawpaw ♪
你抬起你手掌
♪ Or a prickly pear ♪
去碰仙人掌
♪ And you prick a raw paw ♪  ♪ Well, next time beware ♪
它会让你大叫 下次要当心
♪ Don't pick the prickly pear by the paw ♪
学着用你的脑筋
♪ When you pick a pear try to use the claw ♪
如果才能吃到好东西
♪ But you don't need to use the claw ♪
那身上有刺的果实
♪ When you pick a pear of the big pawpaw ♪
就别傻得用手去碰它
♪ Have I given you a clue? ♪
这个道理你懂吗？
Golly, thanks, Baloo.
天哪，谢了，巴鲁
"Pawpaw." Of all the silly gibberish.
啊，天啊 这下子可有得瞧了
Come on, Baggy, get with the beat.
来啊，巴希拉，我们一起唱啊
♪ The bare necessities of life will come to you ♪
那生活必需品会自动找上你
♪ They'll come to me! ♪
快找上我 会找上你
♪ They'll come to you ♪
How 'bout scratchin' that left shoulder while you're up there, Mowgli?
再帮我抓抓痒，左边上面 后背那儿，毛克利
No. Just a hair lower.
低一点，低一点
There. Right there. That's it.
对，对……就是这儿
This is beautiful. That's good.
哦，好舒服啊，我看啊
Kid, we've got to get to a tree. This calls for some big scratchin'.
我得找棵树 用力的好好搓搓它才行
You're lots of fun, Baloo.
你好好玩啊，巴鲁
Right on it.
Yeah!
啊！
That's delicious.
真是个大享受啊
Just a little bit...
看，要再加把劲儿
Yeah!
呀！
啊！
Man. This is really livin'.
哦，天啊，真是舒服呆了
So just try and relax. Yeah.
试着放轻松，享受人生，对
Cool it.
不用担心
Fall apart in my backyard.
照着我的话做，小家伙
'Cause let me tell you somethin', Little Britches...
如果你像蜜蜂一样忙碌
If you act like that bee...
你的生活就太累了
You're workin' too hard.
啊，那毫无意义
And don't spend your time
千万不要固执 浪费时间……
lookin' around for something you want that can't be found.
……去找寻那些虚幻……
……缥渺的东西
♪ When you find out you can live without it ♪
当你学会不再强求你自己
♪ And go along not thinkin' about it ♪
享受，不再忧愁不停 我的话没错
♪ I'll tell you somethin' true ♪
♪ The bare necessities of life will come to you ♪
那生活必需品 会自动找上你
I give up.
哎，我放弃了
Well, I hope his luck holds out.
希望他能带好毛克利
Mowgli, how about you singin'?
毛克利，一块来唱吧
♪ Look for the bare necessities ♪
找寻那生活必需品
♪ The simple bare necessities ♪
最单纯生活必需品
♪ Forget about your worries and your strife ♪
忘掉你所有烦恼和忧虑
Yeah, man!
好棒啊，最单纯生活必需品
♪ I mean, the bare necessities ♪
♪ That's why a bear can rest at ease ♪
充满大自然环境里
With just the bare necessities of life
不要怕，大自然会供应你
Yeah!
耶！
♪ With just the bare necessities of life ♪
知足常乐你会满心欢喜
♪ Yeah, man ♪
耶，帅！
Beautiful. That's real jungle harmony.
太棒了 这森林里面无忧无虑的
I like being a bear.
我好想做只熊啊
That's my boy.
我的乖宝贝儿
You're gonna make one swell bear.
你会是只好熊宝宝的
Why, you even sing like one.
因为你现在像熊一样开心
Yeah.
嘿嘿
♪ Doo-bee-doo ♪
嘟，吡，嘟
♪ Aye-bee doogie-woogie doo ♪
啊，嘟，吡，呜，吡，嘟
Hey, Mowgli, how about you flickin' that ol' mean fly
呃，毛克利，有只讨厌的苍蝇 在你熊爸爸的鼻子上
off of your papa bear's nose?
来把它赶走
Boy, when you flick a fly, you really...
小家伙，你还真会赶苍蝇啊
Why, you flat-nosed, little-eyed, flaky creep!
啊！原来是你们这一群 不知死活的小混蛋啊！
Hey! Let go of me!
嘿！放开我啊！
Take your flea-pickin' hands off of my cub!
快放开我那只小熊宝宝！
Come on and get 'im, champ!
你敢过来吗，笨蛋！
- He ain't no champ! He's a chump! - Baloo!
他那么笨！才不敢呢！ 巴鲁！
Yeah! A big hothead!
对啊！又笨又重大笨蛋！
Okay, you guys asked for it. I'll...
好，这是你们自找的
That'll cool 'im off!
现在不吵了吧！
Gimme back my man cub!
把那个小家伙还给我！
Here he is! Come and get 'im!
他在这儿！自己过来拿吧！
That's how a bear can rest at ease!
熊就是这样悠闲自在啊！
Here's some bare necessities!
给你点生活必需品哦！
Now, just try that again, you...
我警告你们敢再丢……
- What's that you hit him with, son? - That was a bare necessity!
刚刚用什么打他？ 当然是用生活必需品了！
You turn him loose, or I'll jerk a knot in your tail!
听着，耍把戏的，再不放他 我就把你尾巴打结！
We give up!
吓死我了 接着，他来啰！
Here he comes!
Baloo! Catch me!
接住我！巴鲁！
- Baloo! - Back up! Back up! Faster! Faster!
巴鲁！ 快点！这边！
Faster!
快！快点……拜拜！
A rolling bear gathers no hair!
滚球球啰！ 伙伴，我们走啦
Baloo, help me!
巴鲁，巴鲁，救我！
Baloo! They're carrying me away!
别让他们把我带走了！
Bagheera!
巴希拉！
Well, it's happened.
看吧，出事了吧
Took a little longer than I thought, but it's happened.
我就知道交给他没好事
Bagheera!
巴希拉！
You heard me, huh?
哦，你听见了？
Mowgli. Mowgli!
毛克利，毛克利！
All right, what happened? Where's Mowgli?
到底怎么回事？ 小家伙呢？
They ambushed me.
太过分了
Thousands of 'em.
几千只欺负我
I jabbed with my left, then I swung with a right...
我先用左勾拳打 我再用右勾拳捶
For the last time, what happened to Mowgli?
我一再用左勾拳打 我再问你一次
毛克利到底怎么了？
Like I told ya, them mangy monkeys carried him off!
我正要说呀 一群笨猴子把他给抢走了
The ancient ruins.
一群笨猴子
I hate to think what will happen when he meets that king of theirs.
哦，要是让路易王看到了 那就惨了
♪ Dah dee-ding dah-ding-ding ♪
♪ Lode diddly-ohh-zing-boing ♪
♪ Sca-bee-doo, hoo-bi-dee ♪  ♪ Zee-boh-doh-zub ♪
♪ Diddly-ub-doo-dee-moy ♪
♪ I wanna be a man-man ♪  ♪ Mon-mon, lorang ♪
♪ Orangutango-jango ♪
We got him, King Louie!
抓到了！路易王！
Here he is! Man, we got him! We got him!
抓到了！我们抓住人类了！
So, you're the man cub.
哈…… 你就是他们说的小家伙
Crazy!
疯子！
I'm not as crazy as you are. Put me down!
我看，你才是疯子呢 放我下来！
You cut that out!
你们想干什么啦？
Cool it, boy. Unwind yourself.
安静啊，小子，不要又蹦又跳
♪ Doo-doo doo-doo-doo, dee ♪  ♪ Doo-doo dee-doo-doo-doo-dee ♪
Now, come on. Let's shake, cousin.
来吧，握个手……表弟
What do you want me for?
你把我抓来干嘛？
Word has grabbed my royal ear...
现在森林里传说……
Have a banana.
来根香蕉
...that you wanna stay in the jungle.
……你想留在森林里，是吗？
"Stay in the jungle"? I sure do.
留在森林里？嗯，是啊
Good. And ol' King Louie...
嗯，非常好，猩猩王路易
♪ Bah-be-do-bay ♪  ♪ Bu-bu-doo ♪
That's me.
就是我
...can fix it for you.
替你想法子
Have two bananas.
再来两根香蕉
Have we got a deal?
你愿意吗？
Yes, sir, I'll do... I'll do anything to stay in the jungle.
没错，我愿意 只要留在森林里我都愿意
Well, then,
哦，那好
I'll lay it on the line for you.
我先把话说清楚
♪ A-baba-beep-boop ♪  ♪ Boop-ee-doop ♪
♪ Now, I'm the king of the swingers ♪
我是猩猩王国的国王
♪ The jungle VIP ♪
没人能跟我比
♪ I've reached the top and had to stop ♪
我地位崇高受人尊敬
♪ And that's what's been botherin' me ♪
这实在很无趣
♪ I wanna be a man, Man Cub and stroll right into town ♪
我梦寐去当人类 在村落里闲逛
♪ And be just like the other men ♪
像我看到的人类们
♪ I'm tired of monkeyin' around ♪
我厌烦猩猩，就当……
- ♪ Ooh-be-doo ♪  - ♪ Oop-dee-wee ♪
- ♪ I wanna be like you ♪  - ♪ Hop-dee-doo-bee-do-bow ♪
我要和你一样……
♪ I wanna walk like you ♪  ♪ Talk like you ♪
一样的走走路，说说话
- ♪ Too ♪  - ♪ Wee-bee-dee-bee-dee-boo ♪
- ♪ You see it's true ♪  - ♪ Shoo-be-dee-doo ♪
我也看到……
- ♪ An ape like me ♪  - ♪ Scooby-doo-bee-doo-bee ♪
我们是猩猩
♪ Can learn to be ♪
会真的像
♪ Human, too ♪
人们
Wha...
Gee, Cousin Louie, you're doin' real good.
路易表哥，你很像耶
Now here's your part of the deal, cuz.
啊，表弟 先谈谈你得做的
Lay the secret on me of man's red fire.
比方说，教我人类怎么生火
But I don't know how to make fire.
可是我不会生火呀
♪ Now, don't try to kid me, Man Cub ♪
你别想要骗我，小家伙
♪ I made a deal with you ♪
你和我有约定
♪ What I desire is man's red fire ♪
你快教我，如何生火
♪ To make my dream come true ♪
好实现我梦想
♪ Now give me the secret, Man Cub ♪
把这个秘密告诉我
♪ Come on ♪  ♪ Clue me what to do ♪
快说，应该怎么做
♪ Give me the power of man's red flower ♪
快给我力量，生起那火花
♪ So I can be like you ♪
我要和你一样
Fire? So that's what that scoundrel's after.
火？原来这个混球 打这个主意
I'll tear 'im limb from limb.
等我抓到他们
I'll beat 'im. I'll... I'll...
一定要狠狠揍他们一顿
Yeah!
然后！
Well, man, what a beat.
这曲子蛮好听的
Will you stop that silly beat business and listen?
你省省吧，你听我说
This will take brains, not brawn.
只能用脑子，不能靠蛮力
You better believe it, and I'm loaded with both.
你慢慢想吧 我可是早想好了
- Will you listen? - Yeah, yeah.
你不要闹了，好不好？ 哦！好，好
Now, while you create a disturbance, I'll rescue Mowgli.
我要你先去制造一些麻烦
我才能救毛克利
- Got that? - I'm gone, man.
懂吗？
- Solid gone! - Not yet, Baloo!
我这就去，我这就去
慢……慢一点，巴鲁！
♪ Hey, de-zop-ba-nonie ♪
♪ Hap-de-dee-ba-lat ♪  ♪ Da-dat-dat-non ♪
♪ Hey, a-baby-dot-doo ♪  ♪ Zaba-doo-doo-day-doo-bop ♪
♪ Doo-boo-doo-day, ze-bonz ♪  ♪ Za-bop-bop-bobby ♪
- ♪ Za-bah-doo-dee ♪  - ♪ Well, a-ree-bah-naza ♪
- ♪ He-beh-do-beh-doy ♪  - ♪ Well, a-lah-bah-zini ♪
- ♪ Wadahlabat-boodalabat ♪  - ♪ Seebahlalat-dodie ♪
- ♪ Oooh-ooh-ooh ♪  - ♪ Well, a-ha ha ha ♪
♪ Gettin' mad, baby ♪
哇，宝贝
- ♪ You-hoo-hoo ♪  - ♪ Boop-dee-dweet ♪
我和你一样
- ♪ I wanna be like you ♪  - ♪ Bop-dee-oobee-doobee ♪
♪ I wanna walk like you ♪
我想和你一样走走路
♪ Talk like you do ♪
说说话
- ♪ You see it's true ♪  - ♪ Shoo-be-dee-doo ♪
你会看到
- ♪ Someone like me ♪  - ♪ Scooby-dooby-dooby ♪
我们是猩猩
♪ Can learn to be like someone like me ♪
会做得到，就和我一样
♪ Take me home, daddy ♪
快带我回家
♪ Can learn to be like someone like you ♪
会做得到，就和你一样
♪ One more time ♪
再一次 耶！
Yeah!
会做得到，就和我一样
♪ Can learn to be like someone like me ♪
Man!
呃，糗了
- It's Baloo, the bear! - Yeah, that's him!
是巴鲁，大笨熊！ 对，就是他！
How'd that square get in there?
他怎么跑来这儿了？
Baloo! It's you!
巴鲁！是你啊！
Man, that's what I call a swingin' party!
我最喜欢这种热闹的场面了
And furthermore, Baloo,
巴鲁，你看见没有？
Mowgli seems to have man's ability to get into trouble,
毛克利跟人类一样 会闹得天下大乱
and your influence hasn't been exactly...
当然这些还要归功于你的
Keep it down. You're gonna wake up little buddy.
小声一点儿 别把他吵醒了
Well, he's had a big day.
这一天也够他受了
It was a real sockeroo.
连我都累了
You know, it ain't easy learnin' to be like me.
要学得像我一样也不简单啊
A disgraceful performance.
是啊，虽然也不见得有多好
Associating with those undesirable, scatterbrained apes?
不过也难为你了 还得陪那群烦人的笨猴子
I hope Mowgli learned something from that experience.
呃，希望毛克利学到了教训
♪ Scooby-dooby-dooby ♪  ♪ Dooby-doo ♪
嘟比……嘟比嘟
That's my boy.
哈……真是好样的
Nonsense.
嗯，才怪
Baloo.
巴鲁
Over here. I'd like to have a word with you.
过来一下，我有话跟你说
"A word"? You gonna talk some more?
干嘛？又要教训人了？
All right, what's up, Bagheera?
好吧，有话快说啊
Baloo, the man cub must go back to the man-village.
巴鲁
小家伙必须要回到 人类的村落才行
The jungle is not the place for him.
森林不是人呆的地方
I grew up in the jungle. Take a look at me.
我是这儿长大的 不也挺好的嘛
Yes, just look at yourself.
是啊，你有多好啊？
Look at that eye.
你看看你的眼睛
Yeah.
啊！
It's beautiful, ain't it?
多美的眼睛啊
Frankly, you're a disreputable sight.
我直说吧，你可是声名狼藉
Well, you don't look exactly like a basket of fruit yourself.
话说回来 你也不见得过的有声有色啊
Baloo, you can't adopt Mowgli as your son.
巴鲁
你总不能一辈子养着毛克利嘛
Why not?
为什么？
How can I put it?
天……该怎么说你才听得懂？
Baloo, birds of a feather should flock together.
巴鲁
小鸟得跟小鸟生活
You wouldn't marry a panther, would you?
你总不能娶黑豹吧？
I don't know.
我不知道
Come to think of it, no panther ever asked me.
哈……问题是也没有黑豹 跟我求过婚呢
Baloo, you've got to be serious about this.
巴鲁 你可不可以认真一点
Stop worryin', Baggy. Stop worryin'.
哎哟，别担心嘛，老巴 别担心
I'll take care of him.
这事儿我来想法子
Yes, like you did when the monkeys kidnapped him, huh?
嗯，又来了 就像小家伙给猴子抓去一样
- Can't a guy make one mistake? - Not in the jungle.
犯一次错都不行啊？ 森林里就是不行
And another thing, sooner or later Mowgli will meet Shere Khan.
还有啊
我敢说谢利很快就会 找到毛克利
The tiger? What's he got against the kid?
那只老虎？ 他又有什么不满意啊？
He hates man with a vengeance. You know that.
他最恨人类了 你又不是不知道
Because he fears man's gun and man's fire.
他最怕人类的枪跟火
But little Mowgli don't have those things.
可是小毛克利 又没有那些东西
Shere Khan won't wait until he does.
谢利就是怕小家伙长大
He'll get Mowgli while he's young and helpless.
学会了那些东西 所以他就要趁他还小
Just one swipe and...
就一爪子……
Well, what are we gonna do?
那……那我们该怎么办？
We'll do what's best for the boy.
我们得替小家伙想
You better believe it. You name it, and I'll do it.
你放心 你说什么我都做
Good. Then make Mowgli go to the man-village.
好，要毛克利回到 人类的村落去
Are you out of your mind?
你胡说什么？
I promised him he could stay here in the jungle with me.
我答应过毛克利 可以跟我留在这儿的
That's just the point.
你想想清楚耶
As long as he remains with you, he's in danger.
他留在这里跟着你 那有多危险
- So it's up to you. - Why me?
你自己决定 为什么要我？
Because he won't listen to me.
因……因为他已经不理我了
I love that kid.
我喜欢这个小家伙
I love him like he was my own cub.
我觉得他就像我亲生儿子
Then think of what's best for Mowgli and not yourself.
多替毛克利想想 不要只为你自己
Well, can't I wait until morning?
那……我……
可不可以等到天亮再说？
It's morning now.
天已经亮了
Go on, Baloo.
去说吧
Oh, boy.
哦，天啊
Mowgli. Mowgli.
毛克利，毛克利
It's time to get up.
嗯，该起床啰
Hi, Baloo.
哦，嗨，巴鲁
Hi.
嗨
Hey, rub that ol' sleep outta your eyes.
嘿，把眼屎擦掉吧
You and me, we got a long walk ahead of us.
咱们俩得起来上路了
Swell. Gee, we'll have lots of fun together.
哇啊！嘿 我们是要去探险吗？
Sure. Yeah. Yeah.
是啊，是啊
对
All right, let's hit the trail, kid.
呃，小家伙，我们走吧
See ya around, Bagheera.
再见了，巴希拉，我走了
Well, goodbye, Bagheera.
哦，再见了，巴希拉
Me and Baloo, we've got things to do.
我跟巴鲁要去探险了
Goodbye, Man Cub, and good luck.
再见了，小家伙……
……小心点啊
Come on, Baloo.
来吧，巴鲁
All we gotta do is...
我们只要记住……
♪ Look for the bare necessities ♪
找寻那生活必需品
♪ Some good ol' bare necessities ♪
最单纯生活必需品
♪ Forget about your worries and your strife ♪
忘掉你所有烦恼和忧虑
♪ I mean, the bare necessities ♪
最单纯生活必需品
♪ That's why a bear can rest at ease ♪
充满大自然环境里
♪ With just the bare necessities of life ♪
不要怕，大自然会供应你
Yeah!
耶！
♪ I'll live here in the jungle all my life ♪
知足常乐你会满心欢喜
Yeah, man! I like being a bear.
耶，帅！我喜欢做熊
Where we goin', Baloo?
我们要去哪儿？巴鲁
Well, it's...
我们……嗯……我们……嗯
Well, it's sorta new and...
其实我们……
I don't care, as long as I'm with you.
哦，没关系 只要能跟你在一起
Mowgli, look, buddy, there's somethin' I gotta tell ya.
毛克利……小家伙 有件事我想跟你说啊
Tell me what, Baloo?
什么事啊？巴鲁
Gee whiz.
什么事啊……
Now, how did ol' Baggy put it? It's...
嗯…… 巴希拉当初是怎么说的来着？
Mowgli...
啊，毛克利……
You wouldn't marry a panther, would ya?
你总不会娶一只黑豹吧？
Gee, I don't even know what you're talking about.
嗯……你在说什么？ 我怎么都听不懂
Mowgli, don't you realise that you're a human?
毛克利，你必须要了解 你是个人啊
I'm not any more, Baloo. I'm a bear like you.
不，我不是，巴鲁 我现在是一只小熊
- Little buddy, look, listen to me. - Come on, Baloo!
小家伙，你听我说啊 来嘛，巴鲁！来嘛
Mowgli, stop it now. Hold still.
毛克利，不要闹了，你听我说
I wanna tell you something. Now listen to me.
不用跑了 我要跟你说件事，你听我说
What's the matter, ol' Papa Bear?
怎么了嘛？我的熊爸爸
Look, Mowgli, I've been tryin' all morning to tell ya,
我一直想告诉你一件事 其实打从你起床我就想说的
I've got to take you back to the man-village.
你知道，我得送你回 人类村落了
- The man-village? - Now, look, kid, I can explain.
人类的村落？ 我是说……小家伙
- But you said we were partners. - Now, believe me, kid, I...
你听我解释 可是你说过我们可以在一起
- You're just like old Bagheera. - Now just a minute!
我是说过，可是现在……
你跟巴希拉一样 你们都好坏！
That's goin' too far!
不可以这样
你怎么可以说我们坏啊！
Hey, Mowgli! Where you goin'?
嘿，小家伙！你上哪去啊？
Wait a minute! Stop!
别跑！等等我！
Wait!
嘿！
Wait! Listen to ol' Baloo!
嘿！听熊爸爸的话啊！
Mowgli!
毛克利！
Mowgli. Mowgli!
Now what's happened?
巴鲁啊，又怎么了？
Well, you're not gonna believe me, Bagheera,
巴希拉，我想我弄砸了
but look, now, I used the same words you did, and he ran out on me!
我也是依样画葫芦 把你告诉我的说给他听
Well, don't just stand there.
他就跑了！
那……那你还站在这里 干什么？
Let's separate. We've got to find him!
分头找！快去把他找回来！
If anything happens to that little guy, I'll never forgive myself.
哎！要是他有什么三长两短 我这一辈子……
I gotta find him.
也不会原谅我自己的
Mowgli!
毛克利！
快回来啊！
♪ Hup, two, three, four ♪
一，二，三，四
♪ Keep it up, two, three, four ♪
继续，一，二，三，四
What beastly luck.
真被打败了
Confound that ridiculous Colonel Hathi.
怎么会偏偏碰上哈蒂上校呢
Company, sound off!
预备……唱！
♪ We march from here to there ♪
大家踏步向前走
♪ And it doesn't matter where ♪
不管在什么地方
♪ You can hear us push through the deepest bush ♪
跨田野，过上岗
♪ Hup, two, three, four ♪
一，二，三，四
♪ With a military air ♪
以严整的军容
The jungle patrol!
大象要出操了
♪ We're a crackerjack brigade ♪
我们是强人之旅
♪ On a pachyderm parade ♪
在进行厚皮类动物的列行进
♪ But we'd rather stroll to a water hole ♪
可我们更愿意迈步走向水坑
♪ Hup, two, three, four ♪
一，二，三，四
♪ For a furlough in the shade ♪
树阴底下吹凉风
Stop!
等等！
Wait a minute. Halt!
别走，停啊！
Who said "halt"? I give the commands around here.
谁说停啊？ 这里只有我可以发号施令
Well, speak up. Who was it?
谁啊？是谁啊？站出来
It was me, Colonel.
哦，是我，上校
What do you mean, sir, taking over my command?
你在这发号施令 那当我是谁呀？简直太没纪律
Highly irregular, you know.
Colonel, I'm sorry, but I need your help.
哦，上校，对不起啊 我需要你帮忙
Absolutely impossible.
不可能的事啊
We're on a cross-country march.
我们正在演练横贯森林行军
But it's an emergency, Colonel.
可是晚了就来不及了
- The man cub must be found. - Man cub? What man cub?
我们得找到那个小家伙 小家伙？什么小家伙？
How interesting.
啊，有意思了
The one I was taking to the man-village.
上次我要送到 人类村落的小家伙
Good. That's where he belongs.
对，他应该呆在那儿才对
Now, sir, if you don't mind, we'd like to get on with the march.
现在呢，我们要赶路了 麻烦你让一让好吧
No, no, you don't understand, Hathi.
不……不是，你弄错了
He is lost. He ran away.
他跑掉了，找不到了
How delightful.
嗯，天大的好消息
Well, it serves the young whippersnapper right.
哦，那他是有自己的主意啦
But Shere Khan, the tiger,
可……可是谢利回来了
is sure to pick up the man cub's trail.
他找到小家伙就惨了
Shere Khan. Nonsense, old boy.
谢利，笑话，老兄
Shere Khan isn't within miles of here.
他不敢到这儿来的
嗯……
Sorry, Bagheera.
哦，很抱歉，巴希拉 其实生存也是要靠点运气
Fortunes of war and all that sort of thing, you know.
This has gone far enough.
真是越说越不像话
Far enough!
我实在受不了！
Now, just a minute, you pompous old windbag!
听好 你这个自以为是的老家伙！
Winifred! What are you doing out of ranks?
温妮！是谁准许你 出列了？
Never mind.
我自己
How would you like to have our boy lost and alone in the jungle?
我问你，要是今天走丢的是 咱们的儿子，你会怎么样？
Our son, alone?
我们的儿子……走丢了？
But, Winifred, old girl, that's an entirely different matter.
温妮，你怎么能这样比呢？ 这根本是两码事儿嘛
Different, entirely.
哼 哼什么哼啊，温妮
That little boy is no different than our own son.
那个小家伙跟我们的儿子一样
Now you help find him or I'm taking over command.
要是你不肯帮忙的话 以后我来当领队
What? A female leading my herd?
什么？女人来当领队？
Utterly preposterous.
那不鸡飞狗跳才怪呢
Pop, the man cub and I are friends.
爸，我跟他是好朋友
He'll get hurt if we don't find him.
找不到他，他会受伤的
Please, Pop, sir? Please?
好不好？爸
Now, don't you worry, son.
哦，我的乖宝宝，放心
Your father had a plan in mind all the time.
其实在爸爸心里 早就已经有主意了
Sure you did.
哼哼……天知道
Troopers!
注意！
Company, left face!
预备！向左转！
Volunteers for a special mission will step one pace forward.
自愿参加搜索队的
向前一步出列
That's what I like to see.
真不愧是哈蒂上校的军队
Devotion to duty.
同心协力
Now, you volunteers will find the lost man cub.
现在我们要出发去找小家伙
Thank you, Colonel. There's no time to lose.
哦，上校，谢谢你们！ 我们就快去找吧
Yes. Yes.
好……好，别急
Bugler, when the man cub is sighted,
哦，号兵 那你看到那个小家伙的时候
you will sound your trumpet three times.
就吹号，记住，是三长声
Yes, sir.
是，长官
Not now, soldier.
你现在吹什么吹啊你
Sorry, sir.
对不起，长官
Lieutenant, our strategy shall be the element of surprise.
中尉 我们要给他们来个出其不意
You will take one squad and cover the right flank.
你呢，带领一个小队 从右路往前进
Yes, sir.
是，长官
And I shall meet the other squad on the left flank.
我呢，带领一个小队 从左方向前搜
Very well.
好了
Company...
听懂没……
Forward march!
起步走！
Element of surprise?
出其不意？
I say.
对，呃
And now for my rendezvous with the little lost man cub.
那么说……
我也好会会我的小家伙啰
Kaa! It's you!
卡奥，是你啊！
Yes, Man Cub.
是啊！小家伙
So nice to see you again.
遇见你真好啊
Go away. Leave me alone.
哦，走开，少烦我啦
Let me look at you.
让我看看你嘛
You don't want me to look at you?
你不让我看你的话
Then you look at me.
那我让你看
No, sir. I know what you're trying to do, Kaa.
不必了，我知道你 又在打什么主意，噢！
You do?
是吗？
I mean, you don't trust me.
我是说，你是不信任我
- No. - Then there's nothing I can do to help.
不 那我可帮不上忙啰
You want to help me?
你要帮我忙？
Certainly.
是的
I can see to it that you never have to leave this jungle.
我可以保证……
……你不用离开这个森林
How could you do that?
你真的能做到？
I have my own
唔
哦，山人……
subtle little ways.
……自有妙计呀
But first, you must trust me.
不过要记得你得相信我
I don't trust anyone any more.
我再也不相信任何人了
I don't blame you.
我知道他们都骗了你
I'm not like those so-called fair-weather friends of yours.
我不是坏人
以后你不要信那些坏人的话了
You can believe in me.
你绝对可以相信我
♪ Trust in me ♪
相信我
♪ Just in me ♪
别犹豫
♪ Shut your eyes ♪
闭上眼
♪ And trust in me ♪
跟着我来
Hold still, please.
♪ You can sleep ♪
乖乖睡
♪ Safe and sound ♪
香又甜
♪ Knowing I ♪
跟着我
♪ Am around ♪
不停转
♪ Slip into silent slumber ♪
闭上你的小眼睛
♪ Sail on a silver mist ♪
安安稳稳入梦乡
♪ Slowly and surely ♪
不觉中在梦里
♪ Your senses will cease to resist ♪
会让你甜蜜安详
You're snoring.
你在打呼噜
Sorry.
对不起
♪ Trust in me ♪
相信我
♪ And just in me ♪
别犹豫
♪ Shut your eyes ♪
闭上眼
♪ And trust in me ♪
跟着我来
哦？
Now what?
又有人找我？
I'll be right down.
我来了
Yes? Yes? Who is it?
是谁呀？谁呀？
It's me, Shere Khan.
是我，谢利
I'd like a word with you, if you don't mind.
借一步说话，可以吗？
Shere Khan.
谢利，吓了我一跳
What a surprise.
Yes, isn't it? I just dropped by.
真对不起，顺路经过这儿
Forgive me if I've interrupted anything.
打搅了，你正在忙吗？
No, no. Nothing at all.
哦，没……没有，我没事啊
I thought perhaps you were entertaining someone up there in your coils.
我以为你正在上面招呼朋友 是不是呀？
Coils? Someone? No.
上面？朋友？我……没有
I was just curling up for my siesta.
我不过是在上面打个盹儿罢了
But you were singing to someone.
我怎么听到你在唱歌呢
- Who is it, Kaa? - Who?
是谁呀？卡奥
No.
没有啊
I was just singing to myself.
我只是自己在唱歌 唱给自己听
Indeed.
是吗？ 是啊，是……是的
Yes. Yes, you see, I have trouble with my sinuses.
因……因为我喉咙
- What a pity. - You have no idea.
不太舒服 真可怜
哦，好可怜啊
It's simply terrible. I can't eat.
你不知道多麻烦 不能好好吃
I can't sleep, so I sing myself to sleep.
不能睡 所以我才唱歌给自己听嘛
You know, self-hypnosis?
这叫做自我催眠
Let me show you how it works.
我教你怎么唱好不好啊？
♪ Trust in me ♪
相信我
I can't be bothered with that. I have no time for that sort of nonsense.
不必了
我可没时间跟你玩这一套
- Some other time, perhaps? - Perhaps.
那或许下次吧 再说吧
But at the moment I am searching for a man cub.
我正在找一个小家伙
"Man cub"? What man cub?
小家伙？什么小家伙？
The one who's lost.
有个小家伙走丢了
Now, where do you suppose he could be?
你猜他会不会在你这儿？
Search me.
你可以搜啊
That's an excellent idea.
好主意
I'm sure you wouldn't mind showing me your coils, would you, Kaa?
介不介意我看看 你身体其他部分？
Certainly not.
当然不介意
Nothing here, and nothing in here.
这里没有
这里也没有
My sinuses.
喉咙又痛了
Indeed.
继续啊
And now, how about the middle?
现在该中间啦
The middle?
中间？
The middle.
哦，中间
Absolutely nothing in the middle.
你看什么都没有啊
Really?
真的没有？
Well, if you do just happen to see the man cub,
反正你看到那个小家伙的时候
you will inform me first.
记得要先来通知我
- Understand? - I get the point.
懂吗？ 放心，一定会
- Cross my heart, hope to die. - Good show.
我发誓会通知你 那就好
And I must continue my search for the helpless little lad.
我得先走啰 再去碰碰我的运气
Who does he think he's fooling?
哎呀，可真是会大言不惭啊
"Helpless little lad."
有什么了不起
He gives me the shivers.
他还以为真把我给吓死了
Picking on that poor little helpless boy.
可怜的小家伙 为什么这么多麻烦
Yes.
哦，对了
The poor little helpless boy.
还是留在我肚子里比较安全
You told me a lie, Kaa. You said I could trust you.
你也在骗我，卡奥 还叫我相信你呢
It's like you said.
你本来就不应该
You can't trust anyone.
轻易的相信任何人的
If I never see that skinny little shrimp again,
哦，我发誓我永远 不要再见那个小家伙了
it will be too soon.
My sacroiliac.
噢，教我怎么爬呢？
Hey, Flaps. What we gonna do?
小菲尔，今天要做什么？
I don't know. What do you wanna do?
不知道，你想做什么？
I've got it! Let's flap over to the east side of the jungle.
我有了，我们飞到东边那里
They've always got a bit of action, a bit of a swingin' scene.
那里有好多好好玩的 热闹又开心，好不好啊？
Come off it! Things are right dead all over.
哦，无聊透了！ 到别的地方才有趣啊
You mean you wish they were.
满地死尸才有意思呢
Very funny.
一点都不好笑
Okay, so what we gonna do?
好吧，那到底要做什么？
I don't know. What do you wanna do?
我不知道，你想做什么？
Look, Flaps, first I say, "What we gonna do?"
怪了，小菲尔 是我先问你要做什么？
Then you say, "I don't know. What do you wanna do?"
你说不知道 问我要做什么？
"What we gonna do?" "What you wanna do?"
我现在问你，你怎么又问我？
What we gonna do, what you want... Let's do something!
反正总得找点事做做嘛
Okay. What do you want to do?
好嘛，要做什么啊？
Blimey. There you go again. The same notes again.
呃，饶了我好不好？
你又来了，要说几次嘛
I've got it! This time, I've really got it.
我知道！ 这一回我真的有主意啰
So you've got it. So what we gonna do?
哦，你又有了 说吧，我们要做什么？
Hold it, lads. Look. Look what's coming our way.
一群呆子，看 看那是谁走过来了
Hey, what in the world is that?
嘿，那是什么怪物啊？
What a crazy looking bunch of bones.
好像一堆会走路的骨头啊
Yeah, and they're all walking about by themselves.
对啊，那些骨头各走各的哦
- So what we gonna do? - I don't know.
到底要做什么嘛？ 不知道了
Hey, now, don't start that again.
嘿，你不要又来了
Come on, lads. Come on.
去……去 我们去逗逗他
Let's have some fun with this little fella, this Little Bloke, eh?
快去啊，去……去 逗逗他，快去
Blimey! He's got legs like a stork, he has.
我的妈呀！你看他的腿 好像竹竿一样
Like a stork. But he ain't got no feathers, he ain't.
真的像竹竿呢 可惜少了羽毛，难看死了
Go ahead. Laugh. I don't care.
随你们去笑好了，我不在乎
What's wrong with him?
嗯，他是怎么搞的？
I think we overdid it.
我们不该取笑他
We were just having a bit of fun, that's all.
人家不过开个玩笑而已 生气了
Just look at him. Why, the poor little fella.
哎呀，哪有那么多气好生嘛？ 呃，小家伙
You know, he must be down on his luck.
我看他今天一定心情不好
Yeah, or he wouldn't be in our neighbourhood.
对啊，不然也不会到 咱们这儿来了
Hey, new kid! Wait a minute! Hey!
嘿，小家伙 嘿！怎么样了？嘿！
Just leave me alone.
不要烦我了啦
Come on. What's wrong?
怎么样了嘛？天塌下来了吗？
You look like you haven't got a friend in the world.
看样子你一个朋友也没有啊
- I haven't. - Haven't you got a mother or a father?
我没有 那总该有爸爸或妈妈嘛？
No. Nobody wants me around.
没有，没有人要理我
Yeah. We know how you feel.
哦，那我了解了
Nobody wants us around either.
也没有人愿意理我们
We may look a bit shabby, but we've got hearts.
我们看起来不怎么样啊 可是我们心肠好啊
And feelings, too.
很喜欢交朋友
And just to prove it to you, we're going to let you join our little group.
为了证明这一点
我们欢迎你加入我们的行列
Kid, we'd like to make you an honorary vulture.
小子，我们决定选你为 秃鹰之友
Thanks, but I'd rather be on my own alone.
谢谢你们 可是我还是一个人比较好
Now, look, kid.
哎，别这样嘛
Everybody's got to have friends.
每个人都需要朋友的
Hey, fellas, are we his friends?
伙伴们，我们是朋友吗？
♪ We're your friends ♪
我们是你朋友
♪ We're your friends to the bitter end ♪
同甘共苦的好朋友
♪ The bitter end ♪
的好朋友
♪ When you're alone ♪
当你孤单
♪ Who comes around ♪
在你身旁
To pluck you up
给你安慰
Give us a smile.
给你安慰 笑一个
♪ To pluck you up ♪
当你沮丧
♪ When you are down ♪
♪ And when you're outside looking in ♪
每当你倦了归巢
♪ Who's there to open the door? ♪
谁在为你守候大门？
Come on, kid. We need a tenor.
快，你唱第三部
♪ That's ♪
是好朋友
♪ What ♪
♪ Friends are for ♪
♪ Who's always eager to extend ♪
每当你绝望的时候
♪ A friendly claw ♪
伸出援手
♪ That's what friends are for ♪
那是好朋友
♪ And when you're lost ♪
当你迷路
♪ In dire need ♪
需要帮忙的时候只有朋友
♪ Who's at your side ♪
♪ At lightning speed ♪
陪伴着你
♪ We're friends with every creature comin' down the pike ♪
当你不如意我们是你好朋友
♪ In fact, we've never met an animal we didn't like ♪
这世上没有任何动物 我们不喜欢
You take it, kid.
嘿……你听懂了吗？
♪ Didn't like ♪
不喜欢
- ♪ So, you can see we're friends ♪  - ♪ Friends in need ♪
我们是你朋友
♪ We're friends in need and friends indeed ♪
真心真意，永不分离 永不分离
♪ Friends indeed ♪
朋友，朋友 永不分离
Easy, lads. Steady. Watch it!
我们真正的朋友 小心啊，担心跌下来啊
♪ We'll keep you safe in the jungle ♪
♪ Forevermore ♪
不少人知
♪ That's what friends ♪
我是你
♪ Are for ♪
朋友
Bravo. Bravo.
好听，好听
An extraordinary performance.
多精彩的演出啊
And thank you for detaining my victim.
谢谢各位替我保管了我的晚餐
Don't mention it, Your Highness.
哪儿的话，你太客气
卟！
- Let's get out of here. - Gimme room! Gangway!
快走啊 位置给我！
Run, friend! Run!
快跑啊，小家伙！
"Run"? Why should I run?
跑？我为什么要跑啊？
Why should you run?
为什么要跑？
Could it be possible that you don't know who I am?
我看你是不知道我是谁吧？
I know you, all right.
我知道你是谁啊
- You're Shere Khan. - Precisely.
你就是谢利 答对了
Then you should also know that everyone runs from Shere Khan.
那你更应该知道 我是人见人怕的
You don't scare me. I won't run from anyone.
可是我不怕你 谁也别想把我吓跑
You have spirit for one so small,
啊！小小个头志气不小
and such spirit is deserving of a sporting chance.
那我们来玩一个游戏吧
Now, I'm going to close my eyes and count to ten.
现在我闭上眼睛数到十
It makes the chase more interesting... For me.
你就可以开始跑动 开始啰
One,
一……
two, three,
……二，三……
four...
……四……
You're trying my patience.
你在考验我的耐性
...five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
……五，六，七，八，九，十
Run, Mowgli, run!
快跑，毛克利！
Let go, you big oaf!
放开，大笨熊！
Take it easy. Take it easy.
你慢一点，你慢一点 你停下来啊
Hold it. Hold it. Hold it.
Slow! Easy, now!
Easy!
谢利，你慢一点！ 你不要冲动嘛！
He's got a tiger by the tail, he has.
你停下来！
你们看，他抓住老虎尾巴了
And he better hang on, too.
你停下来，不要冲动啊
Take that, you big bully.
看我打你，大坏蛋
Let him have it again, kid! Hit him again, kid! Go on!
再用力一点，小子 继续，再用力一点！
Baloo! Help me!
巴鲁！救我！
Somebody do something with that kid!
快来人帮帮那个孩子啊！
Come on, lads!
去呀，快去呀！
He's safe now! You can let go, Baloo.
他没事了！哈哈哈！ 巴鲁，你可以松手了
Are you kiddin'? There's teeth in the other end.
开玩笑？ 那个家伙正等着吃我呢
I'll kill you for this.
你在找死
Let go! Baloo needs help!
放开我！我要去帮巴鲁！
Fire! That's the only thing Old Stripes is afraid of.
火！老虎怕火啊
You get the fire. We'll do the rest.
你去弄火，我们过去帮忙
Charge!
冲啊！
- Punch and blow! - Stay out of this, you mangy fools!
我要报仇 不准过来，肮脏的笨鸟！
Yeah, yeah. Missed me a mile, he did!
来打呀，嗯，打不到 打不到，大笨虎！
Yeah, pull his blinkin' whiskers!
拔他的胡须啊！
He's a bloomin' pussycat, he is!
瞧，成了嘴上无毛的小猫了
Look behind you, chum.
瞧瞧你的后面
Well, that's the last of him.
看他再敢吓唬我们
Old Stripes took off like a flaming comet, he did.
这次该他抱头鼠窜了
Well, come on. Let's go congratulate our friend.
来，咱们要好好恭喜 我们的小家伙
Hold it, fellas.
慢点，兄弟
Now is not the time for it. Look.
最好先不要再闹了，快看
Baloo?
巴鲁？
Baloo, get up.
巴鲁，起来
Please, get up.
求求你起来
Mowgli, try to understand.
毛克利，你听我说
Bagheera, what's the matter with him?
巴希拉，他怎么了？
You've got to be brave, like Baloo was.
你一定要像巴鲁一样勇敢
You... You don't mean...
你……你是说……
No. Baloo.
哦，不，巴鲁
Now, now. I know how you feel.
乖，乖，我知道你难过
But you must remember, Mowgli,
但是你要记住，毛克利
"Greater love hath no one
巴鲁为了你这个朋友
"than he who lays down his life for his friend."
他牺牲了自己的生命
When great deeds
世界上再也没有像他 那么勇敢的了
are remembered in this jungle,
one name will stand above all others.
大家都会记得森林中
Our friend, Baloo the bear.
我们永远的好朋友，大熊巴鲁
He's crackin' me up.
The memory of Baloo's sacrifice and bravery
他说得好感动
他对整个森林的牺牲和奉献
will forever be engraved on our saddened hearts.
将永远铭记在我们的心中
Beautiful.
好美啊
This spot where Baloo fell will always be a hallowed place in the jungle,
我们现在站的位置
就是这位勇敢的斗士巴鲁
for there lies one of nature's noblest creatures.
生前奋战的光荣地 我们将以他为荣
I wish my mother could have heard this.
我希望我妈妈听到他说的
It's best we leave now.
我们该回去了
Come along, Man Cub.
走吧，小家伙
Hey, don't stop now, Baggy. You're doin' great!
嘿，别停啊，巴希拉 你说得真棒！
There's more. Lots more!
再说嘛，再说呀！
Why, you big fraud!
好小子，你骗人！
You four-flusher!
你……你莫名奇妙啊！
I'm fed up!
我……我受够了！
Baloo, you're all right!
巴鲁，你没事耶！
Who, me? Sure I am.
谁？我？当然了
Never felt... Better.
我从来没这么……好
- You sure had us worried. - I was just takin' five.
害我们都担心死了 嗯，闹着玩嘛
You know, playin' it cool.
就像是耍酷啊
- But he was too easy. - Good old Papa Bear.
逗着你们玩的 我亲爱的熊爸爸
It's going to be a bit dull without the Little Bloke, isn't it?
那小家伙要走了 我会想他的，你呢？
Yeah. So what we gonna do?
会啊，现在做什么啊？
I don't know... Now, don't start that again!
我不知道……嗯 你不要又来了，好不好啊？
Hey, Baggy. Too bad you missed the action.
嘿，巴希拉 你错过一场好戏了
You should have seen how I made a sucker
我斗谢利的时候 先是左勾拳，再来个右勾拳
out of Old Stripes with that left up in his face.
"Boom, boom," I was givin' him. "Wham!"
打在他的脸上
Wanna know somethin'? We're good sparring partners.
我给把他整惨了
我告诉你 小家伙跟我合作得天衣无缝啊
- You'd better believe it. - Yes, sir.
我们是最好的伙伴 不错
Nothing or nobody is ever gonna come between us again.
从今天开始再也没有任何人 可以把我们分开了
♪ My own home ♪
我的家
Look! What's that?
看！那是什么？
- It's the man-village. - No, no. I mean that.
那就是人类的村落 不是，不是，我是说那个
Forget about those. They ain't nothing but trouble.
少看为妙 看多了只会给自己找麻烦
Just a minute. I've never seen one before.
让我看看嘛 我从来没有看过耶
So you've seen one. So let's go.
现在你看过了，咱们可以走了
I'll be right back. I want a better look.
我马上回来 我要看个清楚
- Mowgli, wait a minute! - Baloo.
毛克利，别去啊 嗯，巴鲁
Let him have a better look.
让他去看看吧
♪ Father's hunting in the forest ♪
父亲在森林中打猎
♪ Mother's cooking in the home ♪
母亲在家做顿饭
♪ I must go to fetch the water ♪
我要为我家人取水
♪ Till the day that I am grown ♪
等我长大那一天
♪ Till I'm grown ♪
那一天
♪ I must go to fetch the water ♪
我要为我家人取水
♪ Till the day that I am grown ♪
等我长大那一天
♪ Then I will have a handsome husband ♪
我还会有个英俊丈夫
♪ And a daughter of my own ♪
活泼可爱的女儿
♪ And I'll send her to fetch the water ♪
我也会教她如何取水
♪ I'll be cooking in the home ♪
我在家中做顿饭
♪ Then I'll send her to fetch the water ♪
我也会教她如何取水
♪ I'll be cooking in my home ♪
我在家中做顿饭
- She did that on purpose! - Obviously.
她明明是在故意逗他吧！ 还用你说
Mowgli, come back. Come back.
毛克利，回来，回来
Go on. Go on.
快去啊，快去啊
He's hooked.
他走了
It was inevitable, Baloo.
哎，大自然有它的道理
The boy couldn't help himself.
小家伙也控制不了
It was bound to happen.
就是这么自然
Mowgli is where he belongs now.
毛克利终于回到家了
Yeah.
对
I guess you're right.
看来你说对了
But I still think he'd have made one swell bear.
不过他还是可以 做一只好熊宝宝的
Well, come on, Baggy, buddy.
哎，算了，巴希拉，走吧
Let's get back to where we belong.
我们也该回家了
And get with the beat.
来跳个舞吧
♪ Look for the bare necessities ♪
寻那生活必需品
♪ The simple bare necessities ♪
最单纯生活必需品
♪ Forget about your worries and your strife ♪
忘掉你所有烦恼和忧虑
♪ I mean the bare necessities ♪
最单纯生活必需品
♪ Are Mother Nature's recipes ♪
充满大自然环境里
♪ That bring the bare necessities of life ♪
不要怕，大自然会供应你